Stephen J. Gould papers M1437
Stanford University. Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Series 3: Manuscripts
  - Books
    - Rocks of Ages: Science and Religion in the Fullness of Life
      - Rocks of Ages, annotated typescript, Nature's Cold Bath and Darwin's Defense of NOMA (Box 510, Folder 11)
      - Rocks of Ages, annotated typescript, The Two False Paths of Irenics (Box 510, Folder 12)
    - The Book of Life: An Illustrated History of the Evolution of Life on Earth
      - The Book of Life: An Illustrated History of the Evolution of Life on Earth, dust jacket (Box 360, Folder 2)
      - The Book of Life: An Illustrated History of the Evolution of Life on Earth, promotional flyer (Box 360, Folder 3)
      - The Book of Life: An Illustrated History of the Evolution of Life on Earth, publicity (Box 360, Folder 4)
      - The Book of Life: An Illustrated History of the Evolution of Life on Earth, annotated galley, excerpt (Box 457, Folder 2)
      - The Book of Life: An Illustrated History of the Evolution of Life on Earth, annotated typescript, Reconstructing (And Deconstructing) the Past (Box 457, Folder 3)
      - The Book of Life: An Illustrated History of the Evolution of Life on Earth, reviews and clippings (Box 457, Folder 4)
      - The Book of Life: An Illustrated History of the Evolution of Life on Earth, annotated typescript A Flawed Work in Progress (Box 483, Folder 1)
    - Life's Grandeur: The Spread of Excellence from Plato to Darwin
      - Life's Grandeur, dust jackets (Box 361, Folder 7)
      - Life's Grandeur. jacket design (Box 361, Folder 8)
      - Life's Grandeur. jacket design (Box 371, Folder 15)
    - Adam's Navel and Other Essays
      - Adam's Navel and Other Essays (Box 371, Folder 1)
    - Between Home and Heaven: Contemporary American Landscape Photography
      - Between Home and Heaven, review (Box 457, Folder 1)
    - Crossing Over: Where Art and Science Meet
      - Crossing Over, typescript and pasteups (Box 457, Folder 6)
      - Crossing Over, reviews (Box 491, Folder 10)
      - Crossing Over, typescripts, proofs and correspondence (Box 500, Folder 4)
      - Crossing Over, correspondence and typescript (Box 500, Folder 5)
      - Crossing Over, Table of Contents, notes and typescript (Box 500, Folder 6)
      - Crossing Over, figures, notes, typescript and correspondence (Box 500, Folder 7)
      - Crossing Over, miscellaneous (Box 500, Folder 8)
  - Natural History Magazine Column: This View of Life.
    - Natural History Magazine Column: This View of Life. Published Articles
      - Size & Shape, 1974 January (Box 384, Folder 1)
      - Sizing Up Human Intelligence, 1974 February (Box 384, Folder 2)
      - Race Problem, 1974 March (Box 217, Folder 1)
      - On Heroes and Fools in Science, 1974 August/September (Box 384, Folder 3)
      - The Great Dying, 1974 October (Box 384, Folder 4)
      - Darwin's Delay, and Evolution and the Brain, 1974 December, 1975 January (Box 384, Folder 5)
      - Catastrophes and Steady State Earth, 1975 February (Box 384, Folder 6, Box 217, Folder 2)
      - Velikovsky in Collision, 1975 March (Box 384, Folder 7)
      - Reverend Burnet's Dirty Little Planet, 1975 April (Box 384, Folder 8, Box 217, Folder 3)
      - The Child as Man's Real Father, 1975 May (Box 384, Folder 9)
      - Racism and Recapitulation, 1975 June (Box 217, Folder 4, Box 384, Folder 10)
      - Diversity Through Time, 1975 October (Box 384, Folder 11)
      - Posture Maketh the Man, 1975 November (Box 384, Folder 12)
      - A Threat to Darwinism, 1975 December (Box 384, Folder 13)
      - Darwin and the Captain, 1976 January (Box 384, Folder 14)
      - Human Babies as Embryos, 1976 February (Box 384, Folder 15)
      - Criminal Man Revived, 1976 March (Box 384, Folder 16)
      - Ladders, Bushes, and Human Evolution, 1976 April (Box 384, Folder 17)
      - Biological Potential vs. Biological Determinism, 1976 May (Box 384, Folder 18)
      - The Five Kingdoms, 1976 June (Box 384, Folder 19)
      - The Interpretation of Diagrams, 1976 August/September (Box 384, Folder 20)
      - Darwin's Untimely Burial, 1976 October (Box 384, Folder 21)
      - So Cleverly Kind an Animal, 1976 November (Box 384, Folder 22)
      - The Advantages of Eating Mom, 1976 December (Box 384, Folder 23)
      - The Problem of Perfection, 1977 January (Box 379, Folder 1)
      - The Continental Drift Affair, 1977 February (Box 379, Folder 2)
      - Twin-engined Spaceship Earth, 1977 March (Box 379, Folder 3)
      - The 120-year Bamboo Clock, 1977 April (Box 379, Folder 4)
      - Evolution's Erratic Pace, 1977 May (Box 379, Folder 5)
      - The Return of Hopeful Monsters, 1977 June-July (Box 379, Folder 6)
      - Our Allotted Lifetimes, 1977 August-September (Box 217, Folder 5, Box 379, Folder 7)
      - Sticking Up for Marsupials, 1977 October (Box 379, Folder 8)
      - The Telltale Wishbone, 1977 November (Box 379, Folder 9)
      - Caring Groups and Selfish Genes, 1977 December (Box 379, Folder 10)
      - Nature's Odd Couples, 1978 January (Box 379, Folder 11)
      - An Early Start, 1978 February (Box 379, Folder 12, Box 217, Folder 6)
      - Crazy Old Randolph Kirkpatrick, 1978 March (Box 379, Folder 13)
      - Bathybius Meets Eozoon, 1978 April (Box 380, Folder 1)
      - Were Dinosaurs Dumb?, 1978 May (Box 380, Folder 2)
      - Flaws In a Victorian Veil, 1978 June/July (Box 380, Folder 3)
      - The Great Scablands Debate, 1978 August/September (Box 380, Folder 4)
      - Women's Brains, 1978 October (Box 217, Folder 7, Box 380, Folder 5)
      - The Panda's Peculiar Thumb, 1978 November (Box 380, Folder 6)
      - Senseless Signs of History, 1978 December (Box 380, Folder 7)
      - A Darwinian Paradox, 1979 January (Box 380, Folder 8)
      - Wide Hats and Narrow Minds, 1979 February (Box 380, Folder 9)
      - Piltdown Revisited, 1979 March (Box 380, Folder 10)
      - Time's Vastness, 1979 April (Box 380, Folder 11)
      - Mickey Mouse Meets Konrad Lorenz, 1979 May (Box 380, Folder 12)
      - Our Greatest Evolutionary Step, 1979 June/July (Box 380, Folder 13)
      - A Quahog is a Quahog, 1979 August/September (Box 380, Folder 14)
      - Shades of Lamarck, 1979 October (Box 380, Folder 15)
      - Perceptive Bees, Birds, and Bacteria, 1979 November (Box 217, Folder 8, Box 380, Folder 16)
      - Darwin's Middle Road, 1979 December (Box 380, Folder 17)
      - Wallace's Fatal Flaw, 1980 January (Box 217, Folder 9)
      - In the Midst of Life, 1980 February (Box 381, Folder 1)
      - Death Before Birth, 1980 March (Box 381, Folder 2)
      - Dr. Down's Syndrome, 1980 April (Box 381, Folder 3)
      - The First Forebear, 1980 May (Box 381, Folder 4)
      - The Belt of an Asteroid, 1980 June (Box 381, Folder 5, Box 217, Folder 10)
      - Hen's Teeth and Hore's Toes, 1980 July (Box 381, Folder 6)
      - The Piltdown Conspiracy, 1980 August (Box 381, Folder 7)
      - Vision with a Vengeance, 1980 September (Box 381, Folder 8)
      - Hopeful Monsters, 1980 October (Box 381, Folder 9)
      - Chance Riches, 1980 November (Box 381, Folder 10)
      - Science and Jewish Immigration, 1980 December (Box 381, Folder 11)
      - The Politics of Census, 1981 January (Box 217, Folder 11)
      - Hyena Myths and Realities, 1981 February (Box 217, Folder 12)
      - Kingdoms Without Wheels, 1981 March (Box 217, Folder 13)
      - A Most Chilling Statement, 1981 April (Box 217, Folder 14)
      - The Titular Bishop of Titiopolis, 1981 May (Box 217, Folder 15)
      - Piltdown in Letters, 1981 June (Box 217, Folder 16)
      - What, if Anything, Is a Zebra?, 1981 July (Box 217, Folder 17)
      - What Color is a Zebra?, 1981 August (Box 217, Folder 18)
      - Quaggas, Coiled Oysters, and Flimsy Facts, 1981 September (Box 217, Folder 19)
      - A Visit to Dayton, 1981 October (Box 217, Folder 20)
      - The Ultimate Parasite, 1981 November (Box 217, Folder 21)
      - Agassiz in the Galapagos, 1981 December (Box 217, Folder 22)
      - The Guano Ring, 1982 January (Box 217, Folder 23)
      - Nonmoral Nature, 1982 February (Box 217, Folder 24)
      - Moon, Mann, and Otto, 1982 March (Box 217, Folder 25)
      - The Importance of Trifles (Box 217, Folder 26)
      - Hutton's Purposeful View, 1982 May (Box 217, Folder 27)
      - The Stinkstones of Oeningen, 1982 June (Box 217, Folder 28)
      - The Oddball Human Male, 1982 July (Box 217, Folder 29)
      - Free to Be Extinct, 1982 August (Box 217, Folder 30)
      - Solitary Origins of Some Societies, 1982 September (Box 217, Folder 31)
      - The Hottentot Venus, 1982 October (Box 217, Folder 32)
      - Living with Connections, 1982 November (Box 217, Folder 33)
      - Of Wasps and WASPs, 1982 December (Box 217, Folder 34)
      - On Original Ideas, 1983 January (Box 217, Folder 35)
      - For Want of a Metaphor, 1983 February (Box 217, Folder 36)
      - Unconnected Truths, 1983 March (Box 217, Folder 37)
      - Opus 100, 1983 April (Box 217, Folder 38)
      - Mind and Supermind, 1983 May (Box 217, Folder 39)
      - A Life and Death Tail, 1983 June (Box 217, Folder 40)
      - Sex and Size, 1983 August (Box 217, Folder 41)
      - Darwin at Sea, 1983 September (Box 217, Folder 42)
      - False Premise, Good Science, 1983 October (Box 217, Folder 43)
      - Bound by the Great Chain, 1983 November (Box 217, Folder 44)
      - Chimp on the Chain, 1983 December (Box 217, Folder 45)
      - Just in the Middle, 1984 January (Box 217, Folder 46)
      - The Ediacaran Experiment, 1984 February (Box 217, Folder 47)
      - A Short Way to Corn, 1984 March (Box 217, Folder 48)
      - Continuity, 1984 April (Box 217, Folder 49)
      - Singapore's Patrimony (and Matrimony), 1984 May (Box 217, Folder 50)
      - Adam's Navel, 1984 June (Box 217, Folder 51)
      - Carrie Buck's Daughter, 1984 July (Box 217, Folder 52)
      - The Cosmic Dance of Siva, 1984 August (Box 217, Folder 53)
      - Only His Wings Remained, 1984 September (Box 217, Folder 54)
      - The Rule of Five, 1984 October (Box 217, Folder 55)
      - Human Equality Is a Contingent Fact of History, 1984 November (Box 217, Folder 56)
      - A Most Ingenious Paradox, 1984 December (Box 217, Folder 57)
      - The Sinister and the Trivial, 1985 January (Box 217, Folder 58)
      - Nasty Little Facts, 1985 February (Box 217, Folder 59)
      - The Flamingo's Smile, 1985 March (Box 217, Folder 60)
      - A Clock of Evolution, 1985 April (Box 217, Folder 61)
      - Red Wings in the Sunset, 1985 May (Box 217, Folder 62)
      - Fleeming Jenkin Revisited, 1985 June (Box 217, Folder 63)
      - Here Goes Nothing, 1985 July (Box 217, Folder 64)
      - To Be a Platypus, 1985 August (Box 217, Folder 65)
      - Bligh's Bounty, 1985 September (Box 217, Folder 66)
      - Not Necessarily a Wing, 1985 October (Box 217, Folder 67)
      - Geoffroy and the Homeobox, 1985 November (Box 218, Folder 1)
      - Geoffroy and the Homeobox, 1985 November (Box 452, Folder 1)
      - Treasures in a Taxonomic Wastebasket, 1985 December (Box 218, Folder 2)
      - A Short Way to Big Ends, 1986 January (Box 218, Folder 3)
      - Play it Again, Life, 1986 February (Box 218, Folder 4)
      - On Rereading Edmund Halley, 1986 March (Box 218, Folder 5)
      - Glow, Big Glowworm, 1986 December (Box 218, Folder 6)
      - Soapy Sam's Logic, 1986 April (Box 218, Folder 7)
      - Knight Takes Bishop?, 1986 May (Box 218, Folder 8)
      - Fortitude From Heaven, 1986 June (Box 218, Folder 9)
      - The Egg-a-Day Barrier, 1986 July (Box 218, Folder 10)
      - Linnaean Limits, 1986 August (Box 218, Folder 11)
      - The Archaeopteryx Flap, 1986 September (Box 218, Folder 12)
      - Archetype and Adaptation, 1986 October (Box 218, Folder 13)
      - Of Kiwi Eggs and the Liberty Bell, 1986 November (Box 218, Folder 14)
      - The Panda's Thumb of Technology, 1987 January (Box 218, Folder 15)
      - Freudian Slip, 1987 February (Box 218, Folder 16)
      - Hatracks and Theories, 1987 March (Box 218, Folder 17)
      - Life's Little Joke, 1987 April (Box 218, Folder 18)
      - Empire of the Apes, 1987 May (Box 218, Folder 19)
      - Empire of the Apes, 1987 May (Box 218, Folder 20)
      - Bushes All the Way Down, 1987 June (Box 218, Folder 21)
      - Petrus Camper's Angle, 1987 July (Box 218, Folder 22)
      - An Universal Freckle, 1987 August (Box 218, Folder 23)
      - The Godfather of Disaster, 1987 September (Box 218, Folder 24)
      - Justice Scalia's Misunderstanding, 1987 October (Box 218, Folder 25)
      - William Jennings Bryan's Last Campaign, 1987 November (Box 218, Folder 26)
      - Freud's Phylogenetic Fantasy, 1987 December (Box 218, Folder 27)
      - The Case of the Creeping Fox Terrier Clone, 1988 January (Box 218, Folder 28)
      - The Heart of Terminology, 1988 February (Box 218, Folder 29)
      - Honorable Men and Women, 1988 March (Box 218, Folder 30)
      - Pretty Pebbles, 1988 April (Box 218, Folder 31)
      - A Tale of Three Pictures, 1988 May (Box 218, Folder 32)
      - A Novel Notion of Neanderthal, 1988 June (Box 218, Folder 33)
      - Kropotkin Was No Crackpot, 1988 July (Box 218, Folder 34)
      - In a Jumbled Drawer, 1988 August (Box 218, Folder 35)
      - Genesis and Geology, 1988 September (Box 218, Folder 36)
      - A Web of Tales, 1988 October (Box 218, Folder 37)
      - The Ant and the Plant, 1988 November (Box 218, Folder 38)
      - Ten Thousand Acts of Kindness, 1988 December (Box 218, Folder 39)
      - An Essay on a Pig Roast, 1989 January (Box 218, Folder 40)
      - Grimm's Greatest Tale, 1989 February (Box 218, Folder 41)
      - The Wheel of Fortune and the Wedge of Progress, 1989 March (Box 218, Folder 42)
      - Tires to Sandals, 1989 April (Box 218, Folder 43)
      - George Canning's Left Buttock and the Origin of Species, 1989 May (Box 218, Folder 44)
      - The Passion of Antoine Lavoisier, 1989 June (Box 218, Folder 45)
      - The Chain of Reason vs. the Chain of Thumbs, 1989 July (Box 218, Folder 46)
      - The Dinosaur Rip-off, 1989 August (Box 218, Folder 47)
      - Through a Lens, Darkly, 1989 September (Box 218, Folder 48)
      - Full of Hot Air, 1989 October (Box 218, Folder 49)
      - The Creation Myths of Cooperstown, 1989 November (Box 218, Folder 50)
      - The Horn of Triton, 1989 December (Box 218, Folder 51)
      - Counters and Cable Cars, 1990 January (Box 218, Folder 52)
      - Bully for Brontosaurus, 1990 February (Box 218, Folder 53)
      - An Earful of Jaw, 1990 March (Box 218, Folder 54)
      - Men of the Thirty-third Division, 1990 April (Box 218, Folder 55)
      - Bent out of Shape, 1990 May (Box 218, Folder 56)
      - Everlasting Legends, 1990 June (Box 218, Folder 57)
      - In Touch with Walcott, 1990 July (Box 218, Folder 58)
      - Muller Bros. Moving & Storage, 1990 August (Box 218, Folder 59)
      - The Golden Rule-a Proper Scale for Our Environmental Crisis, 1990 September (Box 218, Folder 60)
      - Enigmas of the Small Shellies, 1990 October (Box 218, Folder 61)
      - The Golden Rule-a Proper Scale for Our Environmental Crisis, 1990 September (Box 218, Folder 60)
      - Enigmas of the Small Shellies, 1990 October (Box 218, Folder 61)
      - Darwin and Paley Meet the Invisible Hand, 1990 November (Box 219, Folder 1)
      - Shoemaker and Morning Star, 1990 December (Box 219, Folder 2)
      - Eight (or Fewer) Little Piggies, 1991 January (Box 219, Folder 3)
      - More Light on Leaves, 1991 February (Box 452, Folder 2)
      - More Light on Leaves, 1991 February (Box 219, Folder 4)
      - The Great Seal Principle, 1991 March (Box 219, Folder 5)
      - What the Immaculate Pigeon Teaches the Burdened Mind, 1991 April (Box 219, Folder 6)
      - Abolish the Recent, 1991 May (Box 219, Folder 7)
      - On the Loss of a Limpet, 1991 June (Box 219, Folder 8)
      - Of Mice and Mosquitoes, 1991 July (Box 219, Folder 9)
      - Opus 200, 1991 August (Box 219, Folder 10)
      - Unenchanted Evening, 1991 September (Box 219, Folder 11)
      - The Moral State of Tahiti--and of Darwin, 1991 October (Box 219, Folder 12)
      - Fall in the House of Ussher, 1991 November (Box 219, Folder 13)
      - The Smoking Gun of Eugenics, 1991 December (Box 219, Folder 14)
      - "The Reversal of Hallucigenia,", 1992 January (Box 219, Folder 15)
      - Mozart and Modularity, 1992 February (Box 219, Folder 16)
      - Does the Stoneless Plum Instruct the Thinking Reed?, 1992 April (Box 219, Folder 17)
      - The Most Unkindest Cut of All, 1992 May (Box 219, Folder 18)
      - We Are All Monkeys' Uncles, 1992 June (Box 219, Folder 19)
      - A Humongous Fungus Among Us, 1992 July (Box 219, Folder 20)
      - Sweetness and Light, 1992 August (Box 219, Folder 21)
      - Magnolias from Moscow, 1992 September (Box 219, Folder 22)
      - Life in a Punctuation, 1992 October (Box 219, Folder 23)
      - 'Red in Tooth Claw,', 1992 November (Box 219, Folder 24)
      - Columbus Cracks and Egg, 1992 December (Box 219, Folder 25)
      - A Special Fondness for Beetles, 1993 January (Box 219, Folder 26)
      - Cordelia's Dilemma, 1993 February (Box 219, Folder 27)
      - Modified Grandeur, 1993 March (Box 219, Folder 28)
      - The First Unmasking of Nature, 1993 April (Box 219, Folder 29)
      - Four Antelopes of the Apocalypse, 1993 May (Box 219, Folder 30)
      - The Invisible Woman, 1993 June (Box 219, Folder 31)
      - Poe's Greatest Hit, 1993 July (Box 219, Folder 32)
      - The Gift of New Questions, 1993 August (Box 219, Folder 33)
      - Fungal Forgery, 1993 September (Box 219, Folder 34)
      - The Razumovsky Duet, 1993 October (Box 219, Folder 35)
      - The Sexual Politics of Classification, 1993 November (Box 219, Folder 36)
      - Four Metaphors in Three Generations, 1993 December (Box 219, Folder 37)
      - Cabinet Museums Revisited, 1994 January (Box 220, Folder 1)
      - In the Mind of the Beholder, 1994 February (Box 220, Folder 2)
      - The Persistently Flat Earth, 1994 March (Box 220, Folder 3)
      - Dousing Diminutive Dennis's Debate, 1994 April (Box 220, Folder 4)
      - Hooking Leviathan by Its Past, 1994 May (Box 220, Folder 5)
      - The Power of This View of Life, 1994 June (Box 220, Folder 6)
      - The Monster's Human Nature, 1994 July (Box 220, Folder 7)
      - Happy Thoughts on a Sunny Day in New York City, 1994 August (Box 220, Folder 8)
      - Lucy on the Earth in Stasis, 1994 September (Box 220, Folder 9)
      - Jove's Thunderbolts, 1994 October (Box 220, Folder 10)
      - The Celestial Mechanic and the Earthly Naturalist, 1994 November (Box 220, Folder 11)
      - Common Pathways of Illumination, 1994 December (Box 220, Folder 12)
      - Of Tongue Worms, Velvet Worms, and Water Bears, 1995 January (Box 220, Folder 13)
      - Ghosts of Bell Curves Past, 1995 February (Box 220, Folder 14)
      - Evolution by Walking, 1995 March (Box 220, Folder 15)
      - Left Snails and Right Minds, 1995 April (Box 220, Folder 16)
      - Speaking of Snails and Scales, 1995 May (Box 220, Folder 17)
      - Age-Old Fallacies of Thinking and Stinking, 1995 June (Box 220, Folder 18)
      - Spin Doctoring Darwin, 1995 July (Box 220, Folder 19)
      - Boyle's Law and Darwin's Details, 1995 August (Box 220, Folder 20)
      - Reversing Established Orders, 1995 September (Box 220, Folder 21)
      - "The Great Western and The Fighting Temeraire,", 1995 October (Box 220, Folder 22)
      - A Sea Horse for All Races, 1995 November (Box 220, Folder 23)
      - The Anatomy Lesson, 1995 December (Box 220, Folder 24)
      - Triumph of the Root-Heads, 1996 January (Box 220, Folder 25)
      - On a Toothed Bird's Place in Nature, 1996 February (Box 220, Folder 26)
      - Microcosm, 1996 March (Box 220, Folder 27)
      - Can We Truly Know Sloth and Rapacity?, 1996 April (Box 221, Folder 1)
      - The Tallest Tale, 1996 May (Box 221, Folder 2)
      - Mr. Sophia's Pony, 1996 June (Box 221, Folder 3)
      - Up Against a Wall, 1996 July (Box 221, Folder 4)
      - A Lesson from the Old Masters, 1996 August (Box 221, Folder 5)
      - The Diet of Worms and the Defenestration of Prague, 1996 September (Box 221, Folder 6)
      - "A Cerion for Christopher,", 1996 October (Box 221, Folder 7)
      - The Dodo in the Caucus Race, 1996 November (Box 221, Folder 8)
      - War of the Worldviews, 1996 December/1997 January (Box 221, Folder 9)
      - As the Worm Turns, 1997 February (Box 221, Folder 10)
      - Nonoverlapping Magisteria, 1997 March (Box 221, Folder 11)
      - Unusual Unity, 1997 April (Box 221, Folder 12)
      - Leonardo's Living Earth, 1997 May (Box 221, Folder 13)
      - Dolly's Fashion and Louis's Passion, 1997 June (Box 221, Folder 14)
      - Seeing Eye to Eye, 1997 July/August (Box 221, Folder 15)
      - Drink Deep, or Taste Not the Pierian Spring, 1997 September (Box 221, Folder 16)
      - A Tale of Two Worksites, 1997 October (Box 221, Folder 17)
      - Room of One's Own, 1997 November (Box 221, Folder 18)
      - The Paradox of the Visibly Irrelevant, 1997 December/1998 January (Box 221, Folder 19)
      - An Awful, Terrible Dinosaurian Irony, 1998 February (Box 221, Folder 20)
      - The Internal Brand of the Scarlet 'W,', 1998 March (Box 221, Folder 21)
      - The Lying Stones of Wurzburg and Marrakech, 1998 April (Box 221, Folder 22)
      - The Sharp-Eyed Lynx Outfoxed by Nature, 1998 May (Box 221, Folder 23)
      - The Sharp-Eyed Lynx Outfoxed by Nature, Part Two, 1998 June (Box 221, Folder 24)
      - On Embryos and Ancestors, 1998 July/August (Box 221, Folder 25)
      - Above All, Do No Harm, 1998 October (Box 221, Folder 26)
      - Writing In The Margins, 1998 November (Box 221, Folder 27)
      - Capturing the Center, 1998 December/1999 January (Box 221, Folder 28)
      - The Pre-Adamite in a Nutshell, 1999 November (Box 221, Folder 29)
      - The Jew and the Jew Stone, 2000 June (Box 331, Folder 14)
      - Linnaeus's Luck?, 2000 September (Box 221, Folder 30)
      - The Gift of New Questions, 1993 August (Box 452, Folder 3)
      - Happy Thoughts on a Sunny Day in New York City, 1994 August (Box 452, Folder 4)
      - Common Pathways of Illumination, 1994 December (Box 452, Folder 5)
      - Speaking of Snails and Scales, 1995 May (Box 452, Folder 6)
      - Age-Old Fallacies of Thinking and Stinking, 1995 June (Box 452, Folder 7)
      - Spin Doctoring Darwin, 1995 July (Box 452, Folder 8)
      - Boyle's Law and Darwin's Details, 1995 August (Box 452, Folder 9)
      - The Anatomy Lesson, 1995 December (Box 452, Folder 10)
      - In the Mind of the Beholder, 1993 (Box 452, Folder 11)
      - Can We Truly Know Sloth and Rapacity?, 1996 April (Box 452, Folder 12)
      - Second-Guessing the Future, 1998 September (Box 452, Folder 13)
      - Bacon Brought Home, 1999 June (Box 452, Folder 14)
      - What Does the Dreaded Word, anyway?, 2000 February (Box 452, Folder 15)
      - Abscheulich! (Atrocious!), 2000 March (Box 452, Folder 16)
      - The First Day of the Rest of Our Life, 2000 April (Box 452, Folder 17)
      - Jim Bowie's Letter and Bill Buckner's Legs, 2000 May (Box 452, Folder 18)
      - The Jew and the Jewstone, 2000 June (Box 452, Folder 19)
      - The Narthex of San Marco and the Pangenetic Paradigm, 2000 July/August (Box 452, Folder 20)
      - Syphilis and the Shepherd of Atlantis, 2000 October (Box 452, Folder 21)
      - Tales of a Feathered Tail, 2000 November (Box 452, Folder 22)
      - The Tallest Tale, annotated, 1996 May (Box 560, Folder 1)
      - Branching Through a Wormhole, 1999 March (Box 560, Folder 2)
      - Lyell's Pillars of Wisdom, 1999 April (Box 560, Folder 3)
      - Pozzuoli's Pillars Revisited, 1999 May (Box 560, Folder 4)
      - The Great Physiologist of Heidelburg, 1999 July-1999 August (Box 560, Folder 5)